I'm back.
Subaru?
Are you all right? Can you get up?
Can you talk?
Emilia.
Emilia isn't the only one
who was worried about you!
What's that look about, I suppose?
It's as if you can't believe the
adorable Betty is standing before y—
Beatrice! Beatrice! Beatrice!
Wh-Wh-What?!
This is too sudden, I suppose!
You... You...
Your face makes me feel so at ease!
It's so cute that
I feel like I'm back home!
I could fall in love!
I really don't want to believe
you meant that as a compliment!
Come on, Subaru. Don't start messing
with us the moment you wake up.
We still don't even know
why you passed out...
Subaru?
What's wrong, I suppose?
It's all right. Betty is here.
Don't cry, Subaru.
Just take slow, deep breaths.
Calm down.
Beatrice and I are both
right here with you.
So, yeah...
It seems like I lost my
memories in the archive.
This might cause a lot
of trouble for you guys,
but I'd appreciate your understanding.
I'm sure you're all very
worried about Subaru.
But we all need
to keep ourselves together,
because no one feels more
anxious than he does right now.
It doesn't look that way to me.
What I want to know is: what kind
of stupid act is this, Barusu?
It's not an act.
I'm being super serious about
telling you all the truth.
My heart's about to
explode from the anxiety.
Very slick.
You speak in that flippant tone
and expect us to believe—
Subaru has no reason to
tell such sick lies.
You should know that, I suppose.
Honestly, Big Brother, you're
just hopeless, aren't you?
What's with that reaction?
You look like you just saw a ghost.
Talk about rude.
Meili...
Oh? So you remember my name, huh?
So what did you forget, then?
I lost what they call episodic memory.
I remember the names of
most people and things,
but my memories of experiences I've
been through with others are murky.
Does that include, say,
what happened yesterday?
Yeah.
Yesterday, eh?
Well... yes, I suppose so.
Really, Master? Again?
How many times are you gonna forget me?
Frankly, it's still a bit
difficult to accept...
but it's likely there's a trap in this
tower that left Natsuki in this state.
I think we should come to terms with that.
Yeah. The archive is the most suspicious,
since that's where Emilia-chan
and Beatrice found me.
It was a pretty shady
place to begin with, too.
"Chan"...
Anyway, sorry I scared you all like that.
I'm sure we all need
time to process things,
so let's take a break.
I'll go with Ram to fetch
water in the meantime.
Let's go, Ram.
You look like you were just about
to ask me to go with you, anyway.
So lewd.
So what was the idea behind that
ridiculous farce back there?
Ram, it's true that I lost my memory.
It's not a lie, a grift, or an evil plot.
My memory is gone.
I don't remember anything but your
names and the relationships we had.
Stop it.
I know we came to this tower to
get back a bunch of stuff we lost,
and that we're trying to
get through its exams.
But that's all.
- My motive is—
- Stop it, Barusu.
- No more.
- And Rem, too... I—
Barusu!
What are you playing at?
What are these...
these ridiculous lies?!
They're not lies.
So you're telling me to believe you?
To believe something as stupid as...
as you forgetting Rem?!
I'm going to get Rem back.
Who do you think you are?
Get her back? You don't
even remember her, do you?!
Barusu... You forgot Rem!
I'll still get her back!
Rem, and my memories, too! All of it!
I'll do every damn thing there is to do,
and then we'll all go home!
We deserve that much, at least.
Considering everything we've
been through in this tower...
Barusu?
Ram, I'm going to get Rem
and my memories back.
I need you to help me do that.
I need help from all of you!
I get that you might never
forgive me for forgetting Rem.
But I promise you this.
What?
I will see this through.
If I give up, you can do
whatever you want to me.
It'll be my penance for being
careless enough to lose my memories
and making you cry.
I'm not crying. Don't be stupid.
C-Come on! It took a lot of
courage for me to say all that!
What part of that took courage?
You were just getting
yourself all worked up.
Also, a promise from you?
Don't make me laugh.
How many promises did I
break up until yesterday?!
How many have you kept?
That's easier to count?!
Man, this Subaru Natsuki
really is worthless, huh?
Why'd you even bring me to this tower?
You butted in.
Also, you did have a knack
for running your mouth.
You could be counted on
to handle odd jobs, too.
What else?
I have short legs, my memory's bad,
I'm a picky eater, and I
don't know when to give up.
You had short legs, your memory
was bad, you were a picky eater,
and you didn't know when to give up.
Yeah, of course.
And...
you cared about Rem.
Barusu, you've truly forgotten Rem, right?
Yeah.
Barusu, you're truly going
to remember her, right?
Yeah. I will.
Not just Rem, but everything else, too.
Very well. I'll overlook this.
On your feet, Barusu.
I was...
Subaru Natsuki was definitely here, right?
Silly. He's just temporarily
invisible at the moment.
Like a flower buried under the cold snow,
he'll show himself once the
snowy season has passed.
I'm sure that's all there is to it.
Last time...
and the time before that...
this place was a complete mess.
It'll happen again and soon.
I have to stop it.
So...
for starters...
Huh?!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
Whoa, there!
Don't go taking that fall in my place.
Now, let's talk.
I'm gonna need you to take
responsibility for killing me.
Responsibility for killing you?
You're being weird again, Big Brother.
After all, if I really wanted to kill you,
wouldn't it have been much
easier to do it outside?
Yeah, I'm sure you had
plenty of opportunities,
but you didn't do it.
Right? So—
If your intent to kill me didn't exist
until this morning, that's different.
Or should I say sometime after the whole
chain reaction that started last night?
Don't tell me...
Were you lying about losing your
memories just to set me up?
Don't get the wrong idea, Meili.
It's no lie that I lost my memory.
It's true, which is why this is serious.
That in itself brings up
some questions, but...
How are you planning to
finish me off, then?
Are you gonna push me off
these stairs for revenge?
My mean little beasties
aren't with me now, so...
I have no intention of
killing or hurting you.
I intend to treat you the same
as I have been for all this time.
Thankfully, I stopped your crime
before you could carry it out,
so as long as I don't tell anyone,
we can pretend it never happened.
Wh-What are you...
But now you understand, right?
It's gonna be pretty risky
to try to do anything to me.
If you still want to try, well...
let's at least talk it over.
If something's bothering you,
I'll listen as best I can.
Bothering me?
If anything bothers me,
it's this situation right now!
I can't believe you!
You don't even know
what I was trying to do!
This makes no sense otherwise!
Because if you did...
It was an unpredictable act on your part.
Just an impulse.
You just don't have any other
way of resolving problems.
And that's not your fault.
Because... murder is a habit.
Don't talk like you know anything!
What... What the hell...
could you possibly know about me?!
I do know.
Meili, I know all about you.
This might sound creepy,
but I doubt there's anyone in this
world who knows you better than I do.
Elsa Granhiert.
She's the reason you tried
to kill me, right?
I won't... let anyone...
talk as if they understand me.
I think Elsa Granhiert was
an unbelievable woman.
I've been told to bring you back.
So you'll be coming with me.
What's wrong?
Stop that. It tickles.
I'm not too particular
about clothing, either,
but you are definitely a strange one.
So very temperamental.
Aren't you, Meili?
It seems that's your name.
It's stitched into those
rags you were wearing.
They might belong to someone else,
but not having a name to
call you is inconvenient, so...
You are Meili.
That's what I'm going to call you.
If you say you lost everything,
forgot everything,
then why don't I teach you?
That's a mother's job, after all.
I think Elsa Granhiert
was a detestable woman.
Are you shivering?
Perhaps you're cold?
Stop that. It tickles.
I saw every job through.
I modeled my methods after Elsa's.
I learned to speak.
I modeled my speech after Elsa's.
I even wore clothes.
I modeled my fashion sense after Elsa's.
And I kept all that secret from Elsa.
I think Elsa Granhiert
was a dreadful woman.
Meili, could you braid my
hair? I can't be bothered.
Meili, are you listening?
I asked you to braid my hair.
Yes, I heard you.
Honestly, you're such a slob.
Grr.
Excuse me? That tickles.
You're such a funny girl.
I didn't want her to disappear after
she'd become a huge presence in my mind.
She had become an unbelievable,
detestable, dreadful part of my life.
Not even just "a part."
She was so much bigger than that.
So if that all had to be exposed...
If it had to be trampled on...
If Elsa Granhiert had to be killed...
then Meili Portroute...
It would've been so much better
if you had just let me end it.
Yeah, sorry.
But while most people take off their
shoes when entering someone's home,
it's the Natsuki family way to just
barge right into the hearts of others.
You wanted to avenge her?
I don't know.
Even if that's the case, Elsa...
...wouldn't have wanted that.
I know that much.
Why do you keep trying to help me?
I've already forgotten almost everything.
If I lost you, too, that'd be
one more thing for me to miss.
I guess that's why.
Meili, I get that you don't know
what to do with your own feelings.
But I doubt you're gonna be able
to find all the answers right away.
So let me handle things here.
I won't let things go bad.
Or at least, I'll do my best
not to let them go bad.
As long as that's what you want, too.
I can't... believe that.
It's easy for you to
say whatever you want.
Then don't consider it a promise with me.
Consider it a promise with all of us.
Yes. It's all right.
I was listening, so I'm a
witness to that promise.
You're a lifesaver, Emilia-chan!
Frankly, I didn't even feel
like I was alive.
That's what I should be saying!
I can't believe you tried
to jump with her!
I thought my heart was going
to leap out of my chest!
Big Sister...
You were... listening?
Yes. Subaru said he wanted me
to help if you got into trouble.
Listen, Meili.
I believe what Subaru said.
So I want you to believe him, too.
Believe us both.
This tower in the sand is too small a
place for you to make any big decisions.
Look for your answers once we're
out of here and in a bigger place.
We'll all do our very best, too.
I don't want to forget about Elsa.
Yeah. That's fine.
There's no need to
forget someone you like.
Though... it might be better if you
didn't try to do things the way she did.
I see. It appears you took care of things.
Not a bad job. My compliments.
Perhaps I don't need to say it,
but she has been waiting most
anxiously for your return.
You're right. You didn't need to say that.
Learn some restraint, Echidna.
This is the attitude you take the moment
you find out I'm controlling this body.
Just how I want it.
Frankly, I was beside myself with worry.
I held it in because Subaru
asked me to, I suppose.
But are you really
sure about this, Master?
She tried to kill you, y'know.
You really don't think
she should be punished?
It's fine. Meili's already
been through her punishment.
Things turned out this
way because no one ever
taught her why she was being punished.
So I'm gonna teach her that going forward.
I'll need your help, too, of course.
Mine?
Well, sure. Everyone in this
tower is gonna be her textbook.
So don't do anything that
would set a bad example.
Me, too?
Master and me...
Uh, what's with you?
Nothing!
I'll raise her up into a model
citizen! Just you watch!
Hey, Big Brother!
You put weird ideas in the naked
lady's head again, didn't you?!
So I can take this to mean
that she is not an issue?
Yep, that's right.
Although what happens from
now on is up to Meili,
who's gonna grow up watching our backs.
So don't let your back
look spineless, yeah?
I see. It's a matter of appearances.
In that case, you can count on me.
I expect the best, Mr. Knight!
You and I are the closest things
she has to a father, after all.
Then we will have to
give it our best effort.
Yeah! Bring it on!
Th-That's right! I'm going
to treat Meili as...
FROM NOW ON
Just a suggestion...
but why don't we put my
amnesia aside for now?
What?
I'm really happy that you want
to help me get my memory back,
but no one here believes the tower
had nothing to do with it, right?
I'm saying there's some connection
between this tower and my amnesia.
In other words, if we meet the
requirements to conquer the tower,
we'll find the reason for
your amnesia in the process,
and maybe even the key to fixing it.
Is that it?
Yes, yes! Exactly!
Of course...
that doesn't mean I think
I should just stay this way.
But I want to do what we came here to do.
I'll endure the difficulty
this time... but...
But?
Let me worry about you more than anyone
else every now and then, all right?
Uh... sorry.
Emilia said what I was
going to say, I suppose.
You'd better reflect long
and hard on this.
Yeah, I know.
And what, specifically,
are we going to do?
First of all, we need
to get past the exams.
And the best way to do that is to figure
out what Reid's weakness is, right?
So...
why don't we all search the
archive for Reid's book?